Guide to the Lantern Slide Collection [ca. 1860-1942] PR 70
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
Lantern Slide Collection
[ca. 1860-1942]
PR 70
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
84.88 Linear feet (4,869 items)
The collection consists of 4,869 lantern slide photographs, most are 3 1/4 x 4 in. and were manufactured between 1860 and 1942. Many slides were connected with lecture presentations about New York and early American life sponsored by the New-York Historical Society. Some are also original photographs of views of Manhattan neighborhoods such as the Lower East Side, Greenwich Village, and Harlem as well as the borough of the Bronx. Images include bridges, rivers, transportation, churches, clubs, commercial and public buildings, monuments, parks, residences, schools, streets and theaters. Other interesting parts of the collection include a series on circus advertisements, several groups of cartoons and caricatures, and World War I American training camp slides. Some slides are copies of drawings that date back as far as the mid-17th century. Also in the collection are groups of slides manufactured outside the United States, including Germany, France, and Italy; most are tourist views. The Songs and Announcements sections of the collection contains slides used in theaters. The song slides were used to illustrate accompanying music and cover such genres as religious, popular, and patriotic music. The announcement slides provided reminders to viewers, such as removing their hats, or the slides advertised local businesses. Slides from amateur photographic clubs such as the American Slide Interchange, the Camera Club of New York, and the Society of Amateur Photographers of New York also account for a large portion of the collection.
Provenance
The collection's accession dates span from 1911 to 1955. See the Quarterly/Annual Reports in the Transparency File for descriptions of specific group accessions.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers.
Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to 30 photocopies per day per person. Suitability of the original for photocopying is at the discretion of the staff. Neither blueprints nor tracings can be copied under any circumstances. Duplication of large-format items will be done by the house photographer. See Print Room guidelines for details.
Historical Note
Lantern slides are positive images on glass that were intended to be projected for viewing. In most cases, the emulsion is protected by a second piece of thin glass, and the unit is secured around all four edges with black paper tape. Many are individual, hand-painted works.
Lantern slides came into wide use in the United States after the 1860s. During the 1890s, magic lanterns were in high fashion as an extension of photography. Lantern slide shows, or the magic lantern, became popular home entertainment and served as an accompaniment to speakers on the lecture circuit. Lantern slides reached their popularity about 1900 and continued to be widely used until the 1930s, when they were gradually replaced by the more convenient 35-mm slides.
Scope and Content Note
The Lantern Slides Collection contains 4,869 items, and makes up the bulk of the Transparency File (PR-70). The majority are 3 1/4 x 4 inch lantern slide photographs, many of which resulted from N-YHS' sponsorship, from 1900 to 1950, of numerous illustrated lectures about New York and early American life. Some of the slides in this collection are also original photographs of views of such Manhattan neighborhoods as the Lower East Side, Greenwich Village and Harlem. Well-represented photographers include Charles Simpson, Richard Hoe Lawrence and George E. Stonebridge. Among the dominant lantern slide manufacturers are the Charles Beseler Lantern Slide Co., Edward Van Altena, and T.H. McAllister-Keller and Co. Slides from amateur photographic clubs, such as the American Slide Interchange, the Camera club of New York, and the Society of Amateur Photographers of New York also account for a large portion of the collection.
The collection also contains a series of Circus advertisements, several groups of Cartoons and Caricatures, and a group of World War I American Training slides. Also included are groups of slides manufactured in countries outside of the United States, including Germany, France and Italy. Most of these are tourist views, but a few were produced by unidentified amateur photographers.
The majority of the images in the collection are relevant to New York City, and include bridges, rivers and transportation (including railroad material). Borough-specific New York City material includes subjects such as Churches, Clubs, Commercial Buildings, Monuments, Parks, Residences, Schools, Streets, and Theaters. As a whole, this portion of the collection provides a thorough look at the streets, culture and history of New York city throughout the late 1800s and early 1900s. Some of the slides are also copy work produced during that time of drawings that date as far back as the mid-17th century, functioning as examples of the sorts of images which 19th and 20th century slide makers and sponsors felt were worthy of preserving.
The Songs and Announcements sections of the collection contain slides which were used in the theaters. The announcements reminded viewers to take off their hats or go to a nearby ice cream shop after the show. The song slides were used to illustrate accompanying music, and cover such genres as religious, popular, and patriotic music.
Arrangement
The Lantern slides are organized into three series. Slides in the "General" category are further organized by location, subject matter, or photographer. The most specific (nearly item-level) cataloging has been done with slides pertaining to New York City, and these are arranged by borough.
Series I: General Lantern Slides
Series II: Songs
Series III: Announcements
American Slide Interchange; Camera Club of New York; Charles Beseler Co.; Dodd, George C.; Lawrence, Richard Hoe; Simpson, Charles; Society of Amateur Photographers of New York; Stonebridge, George E.; T.H. McAllister-Keller Co.; Van Altena, Edward; Advertising--Circus; Announcements; Bridges--New York (State)--New York; Bronx (New York, N.Y.)--Description and travel; Caricatures and cartoons; Chelsea (Manhattan, New York, N.Y.); Church buildings--New York (State)--New York; Clubs--New York (State)--New York; Commercial buildings--New York (State)--New York; Drawing; Dwellings--New York (State)--New York; France--Description and travel; Germany--Description and travel; Greenwich Village (New York, N.Y.); Harlem (New York, N.Y.); Italy--Description and travel; Lantern slides; Lower East Side (New York, N.Y.); Military training camps--United States; Monuments--New York (State)--New York; New York (N.Y.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; New York (N.Y.)--Description and travel; New York (N.Y.)--Social life and customs; Parks--New York (State)--New York; Public buildings--New York (State)--New York; Rivers--New York (State)--New York; School buildings--New York (State)--New York; Songs--Texts; Streets--New York (State)--New York; Theaters--New York (State)--New York; Transparencies; Transportation--New York (State)--New York; United States--Social life and customs; World War, 1914-1918--United States; Yorkville (New York, N.Y.)
- Series I: General Lantern Slides
  - Copy Slides--"An Authentic Narrative…the Death of Major Andre…" by Joshua Hett Smith, Esq. (Box 1)
  - Copy Slides--Museums (Box 2)
  - Copy Slides--Museums (Box 3)
  - Copy Slides--New York City Hotels (Box 4)
  - Copy Slides--New York City Hotels (Box 5)
  - Copy Slides--New York City Hotels (Box 6)
  - Copy Slides--New York City Hotels (Box 7)
  - Copy Slides--World News 1912-1913 (Box 8)
  - Copy Slides--World News 1912-1913 (Box 9)
  - Copy Slides--World News 1912-1913 (Box 10)
  - Lectures--"Stereopticon Views of the Great Blizzard of 1888" by Mr. Washbourn (Box 10)
  - Lectures--"Stereopticon Views of the Great Blizzard of 1888" by Mr. Washbourn (Box 11)
  - Photographers (Box 11)
  - Photographers--Burton, Thomas J. (Box 11)
  - Photographers--Foster, T. (Box 11)
  - Photographers--Hibbard, C.C. (Box 11)
  - Photographers--Hull, Charles Wager (Box 12)
  - Photographers--Langill & Bodfish (Box 12)
  - Photographers--Lawrence, Richard Hoe (Box 12)
  - Photographers--Morris, Charles E. (Box 12)
  - Photographers--Oppenheim, William George (Box 12)
  - Photographers--Rau, William H. (Box 12)
  - Photographers--Schoen, A.P. (Box 12)
  - Photographers--Simpson, Charles (Box 13)
  - Photographers--Simpson, Charles (Box 14)
  - Photographers--Simpson, Charles (Box 15)
  - Photographers--Stonebridge (Box 15)
  - Photographers--Stonebridge (Box 16)
  - Photographers--Stonebridge (Box 17)
  - Photographers--Stonebridge (Box 18)
  - Photographers--Stonebridge (Box 19)
  - Photographers--Tiemann, H.N. (Box 19)
  - Photographers--Uhle, John Bethell (Box 19)
  - Photographers--Van Altena, Edward (Box 19)
  - Photographers--Warrin, Ernest (Box 19)
  - Portraits--Group (Box 19)
  - Portraits--Individual (Box 20)
  - Series--American Colonial Life (Box 20)
  - Series--Architectural Photographs (Box 21)
  - Series--Architectural Photographs (Box 22)
  - Series--Architectural Photographs (Box 23)
  - Series--Architectural Photographs (Box 24)
  - Series--Audubon and New York Views (Box 24)
  - Series--Blizzard of 1888 (Box 25)
  - Series--Circuses & shows (Box 25)
  - Series--Circuses & shows (Box 26)
  - Series--Europe (Box 27)
  - Series--Farm Life (Box 27)
  - Series--Farm Life (Box 28)
  - Series--Gilbert's Elevated Railroad and Pneumatic Dispatch (Box 28)
  - Series--Lake George Resort Life (Box 28)
  - Series--Lake George Resort Life (Box 29)
  - Series--New York City Views (Box 29)
  - Series--New York City Views (Box 30)
  - Series--Portraits (Box 30)
  - Series--Society of Amateur Photographers of N.Y.? (Box 30)
  - Series--Society of Amateur Photographers of N.Y.? (Box 31)
  - Series--Upstate New York (Box 31)
  - Series--Upstate New York (Box 32)
  - Series--Upstate New York (Box 33)
  - Series--Upstate New York (Box 34)
  - Subjects--American Revolution (Box 34)
  - Subjects--Archaeology (Box 34)
  - Subjects--Cartoons (Commentary) (Box 34)
  - Subjects--Cartoons (Commentary) (Box 35)
  - Subjects--Cartoons (Commentary)--Ethnic stereotypes (Box 35)
  - Subjects--Cartoons (Commentary)--Political Cartoons (Box 35)
  - Subjects--Executions (Law) (Box 35)
  - Subjects--Fashion (Box 35)
  - Subjects--Fashion (Box 36)
  - Subjects--Fire fighters (Box 36)
  - Subjects--Indians of North America (Box 36)
  - Subjects--Military (Box 36)
  - Subjects--Parades and Processions (Box 36)
  - Subjects--Parades and Processions (Box 37)
  - Subjects--Rivers (Box 37)
  - Subjects--Ships (Box 37)
  - Subjects--Ships--Ocean Liners (Box 37)
  - Subjects--Ships--Ocean Liners (Box 38)
  - Subjects--Ships--Steamboats (Box 38)
  - Subjects--Spanish-American War (Box 38)
  - Subjects--Transportation (Box 38)
  - Subjects--Transportation--Railroads (Box 38)
  - Subjects--Views (Box 38)
  - Subjects--World War I--American Training Camps (Box 38)
  - Subjects--World War I--American Training Camps (Box 39)
  - Subjects--World War I--Ships (Box 39)
  - Subjects--World War I--Ships (Box 40)
  - Subjects--World War II (Box 40)
  - Unidentified--Buildings (Box 40)
  - Unidentified--Engraving Reproductions (Box 40)
  - Unidentified--Residences (Box 40)
  - Unidentified--Residences (Box 41)
  - Unidentified--Streets (Box 41)
  - Asia-Japan (Box 41)
  - Europe (Box 41)
  - Europe-France (Box 41)
  - Europe-France (Box 41)
  - Europe-Germany (Box 41)
  - Europe-Italy (Box 41)
  - Europe-Russia (Box 42)
  - Europe-Spain-Seville (Box 42)
  - Arizona (Box 42)
  - California (Box 42)
  - Colorado (Box 42)
  - District of Columbia-Washington (Box 42)
  - Maryland (Box 42)
  - Massachusetts (Box 42)
  - Massachusetts-Boston (Box 42)
  - Massachusetts-Cambridge (Box 43)
  - Massachusetts-Salem (Box 43)
  - North America-Mexico (Box 43)
  - New Hampshire (Box 43)
  - New Jersey (Box 43)
  - New Jersey and New York--Palisades (Box 43)
  - New Jersey and New York-Ellis Island--Immigration (Box 43)
  - New York and New Jersey--Hudson River (Box 43)
  - New York--Bridges (Box 43)
  - New York--Churches (Box 43)
  - New York--Clubs and Organizations (Box 43)
  - New York--Government and Public Buildings (Box 44)
  - New York--Monuments and Statues (Box 44)
  - New York--Museums (Box 44)
  - New York--Parks and Squares (Box 44)
  - New York--Residences--Houses and Homes (Box 44)
  - New York--Residences--Houses and Homes (Box 45)
  - New York--Streets (Box 45)
  - New York--Transportation (Box 45)
  - New York-Albany--Harbors (Box 45)
  - New York-Highlands (Box 45)
  - New York-Highlands (Box 45)
  - New York-Kingston--Government and Public Buildings--Senate House (Box 45)
  - New York-Newburgh--Washington's Headquarters (Box 45)
  - New York-Niagara Falls (Box 46)
  - New York-NYC--Bridges (Box 46)
  - New York-NYC--Bridges--Brooklyn Bridge (Box 46)
  - New York-NYC--Bridges--George Washington Bridge (Box 46)
  - New York-NYC--Bridges--Henry Hudson Bridge (Box 46)
  - New York-NYC--Bridges--High Bridge (Box 46)
  - New York-NYC--Bridges--Kissing Bridge (Box 46)
  - New York-NYC--Bridges--Loew Bridge (Box 46)
  - New York-NYC--Bridges--Macomb's Dam Bridge (Box 46)
  - New York-NYC--Bridges--Stone Bridge (Box 46)
  - New York-NYC--Bridges--Third Avenue Bridge (Box 47)
  - New York-NYC--Bridges--Washington Bridge (Box 47)
  - New York-NYC--Rivers--East River (Box 47)
  - New York-NYC--Rivers--East River--Hellgate (Box 47)
  - New York-NYC--Rivers--Harlem River & Ship Canal (Box 47)
  - New York-NYC--Topics--Police (Box 47)
  - New York-NYC--Transportation (Box 47)
  - New York-NYC--Transportation--Railroad Bridges (Box 47)
  - New York-NYC-Bronx--Churches (Box 47)
  - New York-NYC-Bronx--Clubs and Organizations (Box 47)
  - New York-NYC-Bronx--Commercial Buildings--Restaurants and Taverns (Box 47)
  - New York-NYC-Bronx--Commercial Buildings--Stores (Box 48)
  - New York-NYC-Bronx--Government and Public Buildings--Forts--Fort No. 4 (Box 48)
  - New York-NYC-Bronx--Industrial Facilities (Box 48)
  - New York-NYC-Bronx--Monuments and Statues--Tomb of Joseph Rodman Drake (Box 48)
  - New York-NYC-Bronx--Parades and Processions (Box 48)
  - New York-NYC-Bronx--Parks and Squares--Bronx Zoo (Box 48)
  - New York-NYC-Bronx--Residences--Houses and Homes (Box 48)
  - New York-NYC-Bronx--Residences--Houses and Homes (Box 49)
  - New York-NYC-Bronx--Residences--Houses and Homes--Poe Cottage, interiors (Box 49)
  - New York-NYC-Bronx--Residences--Houses and Homes--Varian House (Box 49)
  - New York-NYC-Bronx--Schools and Colleges (Box 49)
  - New York-NYC-Bronx--Streets (Box 49)
  - New York-NYC-Brooklyn--Churches (Box 49)
  - New York-NYC-Brooklyn--Coney Island--Beaches (Box 49)
  - New York-NYC-Brooklyn--Government and Public Buildings--Forts--Fort Greene (Box 49)
  - New York-NYC-Brooklyn--Harbor--Shipbuilding Industry (Box 49)
  - New York-NYC-Brooklyn--Monuments and Statues (Box 49)
  - New York-NYC-Brooklyn--Museums (Box 49)
  - New York-NYC-Brooklyn--Parks and Squares--Prospect Park (Box 49)
  - New York-NYC-Brooklyn--Residences--Farms--Remsen Farm House (Box 49)
  - New York-NYC-Brooklyn--Residences--Houses and Homes (Box 49)
  - New York-NYC-Brooklyn--Schools and Colleges (Box 50)
  - New York-NYC-Brooklyn--Streets--Park Place (Box 50)
  - New York-NYC-Brooklyn--Transportation (Box 50)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Aerial Views (Box 50)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Aerial Views--Battery (Box 50)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Aerial Views--Financial District (Box 50)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Aerial Views--Midtown (Box 50)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Aerial Views--Upper East Side (Box 51)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Aerial Views--Upper West Side, Heights and Harlems (Box 51)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Cemeteries (Box 51)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches (Box 51)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--Baptist (Box 51)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--Baptist, interiors (Box 51)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--Catholic (Roman) (Box 51)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--Catholic (Roman), interiors (Box 51)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--Dutch Reformed (Box 51)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--Dutch Reformed, interiors (Box 51)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--French-German (Huguenot) (Box 51)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--Friends (Quaker) (Box 52)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--Jewish Synagogues (Box 52)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--Joss Houses (Box 52)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--Lutheran (Box 52)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--Methodist (Box 52)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--Presbyterian (Box 52)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--Protestant Episcopal (Box 52)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--Protestant Episcopal, interiors (Box 52)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--Unidentified (Box 52)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--Unidentified, interiors (Box 53)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Churches--Unitarian (Box 53)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Clubs and Organizations (Box 53)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Clubs and Organizations--Belvedere Club House (Box 53)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Clubs and Organizations--Columbia Yacht Club (Box 53)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Clubs and Organizations--Metropolitan Club (Box 53)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Clubs and Organizations--Union League Club (Box 53)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Commercial Buildings (Box 53)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Commercial Buildings--Banks (Box 53)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Commercial Buildings--Empire State Building (Box 53)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Commercial Buildings--Flatiron Building (Box 53)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Commercial Buildings--Insurance Buildings (Box 53)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Commercial Buildings--Markets (Box 54)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Commercial Buildings--Merchant's Exchange (Box 54)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Commercial Buildings--New York Cotton Exchange (Box 54)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Commercial Buildings--Publishing (Box 54)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Commercial Buildings--Publishing, interiors (Box 54)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Commercial Buildings--Real Estate (Box 54)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Commercial Buildings--Restaurants and Taverns (Box 54)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Commercial Buildings--Restaurants and Taverns--Fraunce's Tavern (Box 55)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Commercial Buildings--Shops (Box 55)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Commercial Buildings--Shops, Interiors (Box 55)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Commercial Buildings--Singer Building (Box 55)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Commercial Buildings--Washington Building (Box 55)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Commercial Buildings--Whitehall Building (Box 55)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--From the Water (Box 55)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--From the Water (Box 56)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Government and Public Buildings (Box 56)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Government and Public Buildings--Aquariums (Box 56)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Government and Public Buildings--Aquariums, interiors (Box 56)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Government and Public Buildings--Barge Office (Box 56)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Government and Public Buildings--Castle Garden (Box 56)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Government and Public Buildings--Castle Garden, interiors (Box 56)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Government and Public Buildings--City Hall (Box 57)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Government and Public Buildings--City Hall, interiors (Box 57)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Government and Public Buildings--City Hall--Hall of Records (Box 57)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Government and Public Buildings--Courthouses (Box 57)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Government and Public Buildings--Custom Houses (Box 57)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Government and Public Buildings--Detention Facilities (Box 57)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Government and Public Buildings--Federal Hall (Box 58)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Government and Public Buildings--Federal Hall, interiors (Box 58)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Government and Public Buildings--Forts (Box 58)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Government and Public Buildings--Forts--Fort Amsterdam (Box 58)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Government and Public Buildings--Forts--Fort Amsterdam, interiors (Box 58)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Government and Public Buildings--Forts--Fort Gansevoort (Box 58)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Government and Public Buildings--Forts--Fort George (Box 58)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Government and Public Buildings--Forts--Fort Tryon (Box 58)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Government and Public Buildings--Forts--Fort Washington (Box 58)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Government and Public Buildings--Government House (Box 58)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Government and Public Buildings--Hospitals (Box 59)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Government and Public Buildings--Institutions (Box 59)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Government and Public Buildings--Post Office (Box 59)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Government and Public Buildings--Register's Office (Box 59)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Government and Public Buildings--Reservoir (Box 59)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Government and Public Buildings--Stadt Huys (Box 59)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Government and Public Buildings--Tammany Hall (Box 59)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Government and Public Buildings--Treasury (Box 59)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Government and Public Buildings--Welfare Facilities (Box 59)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Harbor (Box 60)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Harbor--Battery (Box 60)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Harbor--Ferry Terminals & Slips (Box 60)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Harbor--Piers and Wharves (Box 60)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Harbor--Shipbuilding Industry (Box 60)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Harbor--Steamboats (Box 60)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Hotels (Box 61)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Libraries (Box 61)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Libraries, interiors (Box 61)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Monuments and Statues (Box 61)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Monuments and Statues (Box 62)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Monuments and Statues--Columbia Arch (Box 62)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Monuments and Statues--Dewey Arch (Box 62)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Monuments and Statues--Fort Washington Monument (Box 62)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Monuments and Statues--General Grant National Memorial (Grant's Tomb) (Box 62)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Monuments and Statues--Nathan Hale Statue (Box 62)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Monuments and Statues--Soldiers' and Sailors' Monument (Box 62)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Monuments and Statues--Statue of Liberty (Box 62)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Monuments and Statues--Tomb of St. Clair Pollock (Grave of an Amiable Child) (Box 62)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Monuments and Statues--Tombstone of Major John Smith (Box 62)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Monuments and Statues--Washington Square Arch (Box 62)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Museums (Box 63)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Museums, interiors (Box 63)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Museums--New-York Historical Society (Box 63)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Museums--New-York Historical Society, interiors (Box 64)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Museums--New-York Historical Society, interiors (Box 65)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Parks and Squares (Box 65)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Parks and Squares--Abingdon Square (Box 65)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Parks and Squares--Battery Park (Box 65)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Parks and Squares--Bowling Green (Box 65)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Parks and Squares--Central Park (Box 65)
  - New York-NYC-Manhattan--Parks and Squares--Central Park (Box 66)